<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Shootera</title>
 <link href="http://blog.shootera.in/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://blog.shootera.in/"/>
 <updated>2015-06-03T18:17:41+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://blog.shootera.in</id>
 <author>
   <name>Shootera</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Seven things that show you are a Selfie Addict</title>
   <link href="http://blog.shootera.in/2015/06/03/seven-things-that-show-you-are-a-selfie-addict/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://blog.shootera.in/2015/06/03/seven-things-that-show-you-are-a-selfie-addict</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;ten-things-that-show-you-are-a-selfie-addict-or-may-be-suffering-from-chronic-selfitis&quot;&gt;Ten things that show you are a Selfie Addict or may be suffering from Chronic Selfitis!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;let-me-take-a-selfie-first-is-your-most-used-line-in-a-day&quot;&gt;Let me take a selfie first is your most used line in a day.**&lt;/h4&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2015/6/200.gif&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;you-are-a-master-now-at-the-art-of-taking-selfies-and-have-a-found-a-perfect-side-for-your-selfies&quot;&gt;You are a master now at the art of taking selfies and have a found a perfect side for your selfies!&lt;/h4&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2015/6/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;if-you-dont-post-5-selfies-a-daythe-day-seems-incomplete&quot;&gt;If you don’t post 5 selfies a day,the day seems incomplete.&lt;/h4&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2015/6/giphy3.gif&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;smartphone-seems-incomplete-without-snapchat-and-instagram-click-and-share&quot;&gt;Smartphone seems incomplete without Snapchat and instagram. Click and Share!&lt;/h4&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2015/6/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;you-click-at-least-10-20-selfies-before-stepping-out-from-your-home&quot;&gt;You click at least 10-20 selfies before stepping out from your home.&lt;/h4&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2015/6/5.gif&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;you-have-taken-a-selfie-with-everything-imaginable-food-pets-family-friends-stranger-etc-oh-yes-and-those-bathroom-mirror-selfies-p&quot;&gt;You have taken a selfie with everything imaginable. Food, pets, family, friends, stranger etc. Oh yes and those “bathroom mirror” selfies. :p&lt;/h4&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2015/6/6.gif&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;your-profile-pictures-on-every-social-media-account-is-a-selfie-d&quot;&gt;Your profile pictures on every social media account is a selfie. :D&lt;/h4&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2015/6/7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Point and Shoot Vs DSLR Camera</title>
   <link href="http://blog.shootera.in/2015/05/30/point-and-shoot-vs-dslr-camera/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://blog.shootera.in/2015/05/30/point-and-shoot-vs-dslr-camera</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;broadly-there-are-three-major-things-that-differentiate-a-pas-and-dslr&quot;&gt;Broadly there are three major things that differentiate a PAS and DSLR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Viewfinder Mechanism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sensor Size&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed Vs Interchangeable lenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coming-to-the-naming-of-the-two-types-of-cameras&quot;&gt;Coming to the naming of the two types of camera’s&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pas--point-and-shoot&quot;&gt;PAS : POINT AND SHOOT&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You just need to aim the camera (point) and hit the click button (Shoot) while a DSLR could also be used in the same manner, this why they got this name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dslr--digital-single-lens-reflex&quot;&gt;DSLR : DIGITAL SINGLE LENS REFLEX&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Take out the word Digital. Now what does a SLR (Single Lens Reflex)? This means a camera that has only one lens (which is true for most of the cameras these days). The light in a SLR follows a reflex or  “Reflected path” through the lens to the camera and from camera to the viewfinder where you view and compose your shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;coming-back-to-explain-the-major-differences-between-two-and-what-would-matter-to-you&quot;&gt;Coming back to explain the major differences between two and what would matter to you&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Viewfinder Mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
DSLR’s have a live view finder. PAS have LCD screen as the viewfinder. The viewfinder in the DSLR’s give you an option to view the Scene at the speed of light, or right at the moment when it’s happening. Whereas the PAS first gets the view on to a LCD screen, so there is a slight time lag, as the image needs to be processed and displayed. The viewfinder exists in a DSLR because of an arrangement of mirrors which transfers the view to it, and yes it is because of this arrangement the DSLR’s are oversized than PAS.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensor Size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This difference is less known (almost an underhood difference). But impacts the quality comparison of the images the most. The PAS cameras have a smaller sensor which is where the camera captures the light to make an image. As a rule, the larger the sensor better the image quality. On an average the sensor size is about 10 to 20 times bigger in a DSLR as compared to PAS. Hence better image quality.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed Vs Interchangeable Lenses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A DSLR has an option of changing lots and lots of lenses each for different set of pictures For eg : Portraits, wildlife etc. Where as in with a PAS you are stuck with an optical zoom only and after a certain zoom point the image quality falls and it gets Pixilated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-other-points-of-difference-between-a-pas-and-dslr-are&quot;&gt;Some other points of difference between a PAS and DSLR are&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size&lt;/strong&gt; : PAS are smaller than DSLR.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weigh&lt;/strong&gt; : PAS are lighter than DSLR.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISO&lt;/strong&gt; : DSLR has better performance with low light using high ISO&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background blur&lt;/strong&gt; : PAS cannot give you the background blur you can get with a DSLR&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price&lt;/strong&gt; : PAS are almost always cheaper than DSLR.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative control&lt;/strong&gt; : Most of PAS cameras are full automatic, givin small or no creative control of the photographic capture (you cannot chose aperture and shutter speed in most of the PAS, or even control where the camera is focusing).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lens&lt;/strong&gt; : PAS has a fixed lens, most of the time a zoom one, whereas with a DSLR you can choose the most appropriated lens, being a zoom or prime.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shutter lag&lt;/strong&gt; : most of the PAS have a higher shutter lag (time between you pressing the button of the camera and the picture being effectively taken) than DSLRs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The tradeoffs between choosing a PAS and DSLR are money, size, weight and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tips for a perfect shot of sunrise and sunset</title>
   <link href="http://blog.shootera.in/2015/05/28/tips-for-a-perfect-shot-of-sunrise-and-sunset/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://blog.shootera.in/2015/05/28/tips-for-a-perfect-shot-of-sunrise-and-sunset</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A beautiful sunrise or sunset is the most amazing landscape to do justice with your camera. The first and the foremost Setting you need to do is changing the white balance of your camera to daylight from automatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting-up-your-camera-right&quot;&gt;Setting up your camera right&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set the focus to manual, focus by hand and keep the camera still.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If available use a tripod, and view your composition in it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Switch to manual exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Expose for the sun and the sky, and then move to your subject as underexposure gives richer colors.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aiming-for-a-perfect-composition&quot;&gt;Aiming for a perfect composition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure that you have enough time to check and test for various compositons before the climax!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look for clouds. Blank skies will often give less interesting sunrises or sunsets because there is nothing for the light from the rising or setting sun to illuminate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Watch the Horizon. Don’t put it in the middle of the photo. As the ground is usually dark so you end up with a photo that is half black, use the sensor completely and capture the glorious sky.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look for silhouettes. Get down low to put some flowers in the composition, find a tree or a tree branch and it to your frame which would work as a silhouette. Remember not to put these things in the middle of the picture, they are best suited at bottoms, corners or sides.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep Shooting before and after sunset. As the color of the sky keeps changing and you can never predict it. You never know when the best shot will occur.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Turn around. Sometimes the best picture is just behind you, lit by the golden color of the sunrise or sunset.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-words-of-wisdom&quot;&gt;Some words of wisdom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As there is too much contrast for your camera to capture, you will either end up with detail in the sky and a dark foreground, or detail in the foreground and an overexposed sky. If you choose an exposure so that the foreground is slightly dark, and shoot in raw mode, you can recover much of the shadow detail when you process the image.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You should also make sure that the shutter speed set by the camera is fast enough for you to hand hold the camera steady enough to avoid camera shake. If the shutter speed drops below 1/30sec then you’ll need to put the camera on a tripod, or increase the ISO setting to 200 or 400.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Zoom in all the way or use your strongest telephoto lens and start looking around the sunrise or sunset along the horizon (Do not stare into the sun through your camera, as this can damage your eyes. You may use Live View with your camera, and stare at the sun on your LCD). You will often find amazing color and tonalities&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have fun with shooting the sunrise and the sunset!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to master the art of “Selfie”</title>
   <link href="http://blog.shootera.in/2015/05/27/how-to-master-the-art-of-selfie/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://blog.shootera.in/2015/05/27/how-to-master-the-art-of-selfie</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are living in  generation of smartphones users or more apparently using one then we are quite sure you must have heard the term &lt;em&gt;“Selfie”&lt;/em&gt; and even taken a few for that matter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are surrounded by selfies, and by that we don’t mean they are living and walking with us, rather our social media is so full of them and we all admit that some selfies could really annoy us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Selfie : The concept of taking photos of self using a handheld device, primarily for social networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So lets promise not to annoy our followers and loose count over hard earned and showed off followers over social networks. Let’s pledge to take out 5 minutes and read what is the need of the hour, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Mastering the art of selfies”.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;let-there-be-light&quot;&gt;Let there be light&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use natural light. Stand near a window as this will give your selfie a soft and natural look. Step outside,early mornings or late afternoons are theperfect time for lighting. This will also help in reducing the dark shadows and would not make your Facebook friends think that you party till late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-machocute-side-and-the-bad-angles&quot;&gt;The macho/cute side and the bad angles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, the best thing about being your own photographer is you can bring up your best side and hide the the less flattering side and the trick that works the best to make your face look slimmer is to shoot your selfie from slightly above. For that double chin, stick out your neck just a little. Also for that torso, turn one shoulder slightly towards the camera and start counting the likes once its uploaded ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;filters-filters-filters&quot;&gt;Filters! Filters! Filters!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using a smart phone then use the filters in instagram or other editing tools and do complete justice to your selfie. These filters can really really brighten you up and could make you look cool the way you were trying to, when the shutter just fired!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-so-serious-lets-put-a-smile-on-that-face-as-joker-say&quot;&gt;Why so serious? Let’s put a smile on that face (as joker say)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing wrong in taking your life seriously, but why a selfie, what has that few kb’s of photo done to you, why take it so seriously! And the base line is those serious looking angry young men kind of selfies are really annoying. Your selfie radiates coolness, like you were just out and about and it suddenly occurred to you to turn the camera around and grab photo of yourself, which of course turned out to be awesome offcourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-the-merrier&quot;&gt;More the merrier&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C’mon this could be your new profile picture or an instagram update, you have all the right in the world to have a number of options. So don’t be afraid and take tons of pictures to choose from and remember even the most effortless-looking selfies took time and options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are you waiting for? Step out, have fun and keep clicking!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
